IWW Records 5210
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
IWW Records
1905-1960
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Industrial Workers of the World (IWW)
5210
9.61 cubic feet
9.2 linear ft.
Clippings (information artifacts), memorabilia, pamphlets.
Includes pamphlets, correspondence, clippings and memorabilia relating to IWW strikes, legal cases and mob action against the IWW, and the activities of prominent IWW leaders, including William Haywood, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Joe Hill, and Ralph Chaplin.
3834218
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 12, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Established in Chicago in 1905 by sponsors of socialism and the remnants of previous labor unions, including the Knights of Labor, Western Federation of Miners and the American Labor Union, the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), or "Wobblies", evolved into a radical industrial union which waged campaigns for improved working conditions, wages and hours of work, as well as workers' control in mines, mills, lumber camps and factories.
Scope and Contents
Include pamphlets, official union bulletins, and miscellaneous publications.
The publication files include materials pertaining to union structure, politics, organizing activities, history, strikes, legal cases relating to the union, the imprisonment of union members, and the general subjects of socialism, economics, freedom of speech, and industrial revolution. Pamphlets were prepared by various union members and committees, including Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, William D. Haywood, William Trautmann, and Vincent St. John, There are, in addition, pamphlets written by prominent socialists, academicians, public figures, and social action agencies, including Daniel De Leon, Paul F. Brissenden, Max Eastman, and the American Civil Liberties Union.
Also, bulletins and union newspapers (1922-1953).
Open to researchers in keeping with repository rules.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5177 mf: Industrial Workers of the World Miscellany on Microfilm 5210 G: IWW Graphics 5863 mf: Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm
Anarchism and anarchists--United States.; Criminal syndicalism--United States.; Strikes and lockouts--United States--Research.; Syndicalism--United States.; Centralia Massacre, 1919.; Labor violence. United States.; Strikes and lockouts. Iron mining. United States.; Strikes and lockouts. Miners. United States.; Strikes and lockouts. Textile industry. United States.; Trade-unions. Agricultural workers. United States.; Trade-unions. Building trades. United States.; Trade-unions. Lumbermen. United States.; Trade-unions. Machine industry. United States.; Trade-unions. Metal-workers. United States.; Trade-unions. Miners. United States.; Trade-unions. Petroleum workers. United States.; Trade-unions. Railroads. United States.; Trade-unions. Textile workers. United States.; Trade-unions. United States. Social action.; Trade-unions. United States. Social activity.; Trade-unions. United States. Songs and music.; Brissenden, Paul F. (Paul Frederick), 1885-1974.; Brue`re, Robert W. (Robert Walter), 1876-1964; Chaplin, Ralph (Ralph Hosea), 1887-1961.; De Leon, Daniel, 1852-1914.; Dosch, Arno; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1890-1964; Haywood, Big Bill, 1869-1928.; Hill, Joe, 1879-1915; St. John, Vincent; Trautmann, William (William Ernst), b. 1869; American Civil Liberties Union; Industrial Workers of the World; Industrial Workers of the World. Centralia Publicity Committee.; Industrial Workers of the World. General Defense Committee.; Industrial Workers of the World. Joint Amnesty Committee.; Industrial Workers of the World. Local 8 (Philadelphia, Pa.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 100 (New York, N.Y.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 103 (New York, N.Y.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 110 (Middle West); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 120 (Spokane, Wash.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 210 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 211 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 212 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 213 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 214 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 215 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 216 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 217 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 218 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 219 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 220 (Mont.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 230 (Calif.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 300 (Chicago, Ill.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 330.; Industrial Workers of the World. Local 400 (Chicago, Ill.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 440 (Chicago, Ill.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 510.; Industrial Workers of the World. Local 520 (Chicago, Ill.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 573 (Detroit, Mich.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 600 (Chicago, Ill.); Industrial Workers of the World. Local 1000 (Paterson, N.J.); Ku-Klux Klan; Workers' Prison Relief Committee (Paterson, N.J.)
3834218
- General Executive Board. Minutes, Releases, Statements, 1908-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Proceedings, Reports, 1906-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Proceedings, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Financial reports, 1922-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Form letters, questionnaire, correspondence, 1917-1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Referendums and related documents, 1917-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Organization Charts (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Membership lists and related documents (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Centralia Publicity Committee, 1919-1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Original
- Emergency Joint Branch, Portland, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Everett Prisoners' Defense Committee - Attack on IWW, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- General Defense Committee, 1918-1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- General Defense Committee, California, 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- General Defense Committee, California, California Branch, Bulletin, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- General Defense Committee, California Branch, Financial Reports (Box 2, Folder 7)
- General Defense Committee, Defense News Service (Box 2, Folder 8)
- General Defense Committee, Northwest Branch (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Joint Amnesty Committee - memos on political prisoners, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Mesabi Iron Range Strike, Release and Defense Committee Leaflet, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Minnesota Iron Range Strikers Defense Committee Leaflet, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- New York Defense Committee (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Northwest District Defense Committee (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Workers Prison Relief Committee Introduction on Political Prisoners, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- General Office Bulletin, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- General Office Bulletin, Special, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- General Organization Bulletin, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- General Organization Bulletin, 1943-1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- General Organization Bulletin, 1943-1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- General Organization Bulletin, 1943-1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- General Organization Bulletin, 1943-1953 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- General Organization Bulletin, 1943-1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- General Strike Bulletin, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Philadelphia Local 8, 1920, Marine Transport Workers Bulletin (Box 4, Folder 1)
- New York City, Local 100, Marine Transport Workers Leaflet, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- New York City, Local 103, Workers International Industrial Union Leaflet, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Midwest Local 110, Agricultural Workers (Minutes 1921-1925), (Bulletin 1921-1924) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Midwest Local 110, Agricultural Workers (Minutes, 1921-1925), (Bulletin 1921-1924) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Spokane, Washington Local 120, Lumber Workers, Bulletin - Minutes/Leaflet, 1920-1936 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Montana Locals 210-220, Metal and Coal Workers, Bulletin, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  September 1, 1923
- California Local 230, Oil Workers Financial Statements 1923 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Chicago Local 300, Metal and Machinery, Leaflets, form letter, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Chicago Local 310, General Construction Workers Bulletin, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Chicago Local 310, General Construction Workers Bulletin, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Chicago Local 310, General Construction Workers Bulletin, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Local 330, Building Construction Workers (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Chicago Local 400, Agricultural Workers, Bulletin, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Local 410, Textile Workers, Leaflets, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Chicago Local 440, Metal and Machinery Workers, Newsletter, Bulletin, Minute (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Chicago Local 440, Metal and Machinery Workers, Newsletter, Bulletin, Minutes (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Local 450, Oil Workers (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Spanish
- Washington Local 500, Lumber Workers, Bulletin, Financial Statement, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- New York Local 510, Marine Transport, Leaflets, Bulletin, Minutes (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Chicago Local 520, Railroad Workers, Bulletin, Minutes (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Detroit Local 573, construction Workers, Bulletin, Leaflet, Minutes (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Chicago Local 600, Railroad Workers, Bulletin, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  December 10, 1918
- Butte, Montana Local 800, Metal, Mine workers, By-laws, financial statements, leaflets (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Paterson Local 1000 Textile Workers, Leaflets, Minutes, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Local Documents (Box 5, Folder 13)
- American Civil Liberties Union, Correspondence 1924, "Legal History of Free Speech in the U.S.", 1925, 5 pages - report, 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Appeal, Petition, Indictments, Statement to U.S. Attorney General, Court Cases (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Documentation Concerning Prisoners, 1922-1925 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Leaflets, 1920-1921 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Manuscripts - Memos, Autobiographies, Recollections (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Scattered issues of IWW Newspapers and Bulletins (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 7, Folder 5)
- 12 envelopes - Newspaper Clippings, 1912-1920 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Memorabilia, Broadsides, postcard photographs, Non-IWW publications about IWW, stickers, cartons, authorization cards, membership book and cards (Box 9, Folder 1)
- American Civil Liberties Union. "The Issues in the Centralia Murder Trial." New York, 1920. 8 pages. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The Issues in the Centralia Murder Trial., 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Author: American Civil Liberties Union.
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
- American Civil Liberties Union. "Justice to the I.W.W." New York, 1920. 7 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Justice to the I.W.W., 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 2)
- American Civil Liberties Union. "A Strike is Criminal Syndicalism - In California." New York, 1931. 12 pages, Publication (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: A Strike Is Criminal Syndicalism - In California., 1931; Publication (Box 10, Folder 3)
- American Civil Liberties Union. "The Truth about I.W.W. Prisoners." New York, 1922, Publication (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The Truth About the I.W.W. Prisoners., 1922; Publication (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: The Truth About the I.W.W. Prisoners., 1922; Publication (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Notes: Copy 2.
- Barnett, Eugene. "A Souvenir from the Washington State Penitentiary." no publisher, no date, 22 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: A Souvenir From the Washington State Penitentiary, 1925; Publication (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Author: Eugene Barnett; Elmer S. Smith
    Notes: By Number 9414
- Brissenden, Paul F. "Justice and the I.W.W." 31 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Justice and the I.W.W., Publication (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Author: Paul F. Brissenden
  - Item 2: Justice and the I.W.W., 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Notes: Second edition
  - Item 3: Justice and the I.W.W., Publication (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Justice and the I.W.W., 1922; Publication (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Bruere, Robert W. "Following the Trial of the I.W.W." Reprinted from the New York Evening Post, 1918. 39 pages, Publication (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Following the Trial of the I.W.W., 1918; Publication (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Author: Robert W. Bruere
    Notes: Reprinted from the New York Evening Post
  - Item 2: Following the Trial of the I.W.W., 1918; Publication (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Notes: Reprinted from the New York Evening Post. Photocopy.
- Bureau of Industrial Research. "Agriculture: The World's Basic Industry and Its Workers." Chicago, Illinois no date. 64 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Agriculture: The World's Basic Industry and Its Workers., 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Author: Bureau of Industrial Research.
  - Item 2: Agriculture: The World's Basic Industry and Its Workers., 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Cannon, James P. "The I.W.W.: The Great Anticipation." New York: Pioneer Publishing, 1956. 44 pages, Publication (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: The I.W.W.: The Great Anticipation., 1956; Publication (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Author: James P. Cannon
    Notes: On the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Founding Convention
- Chaplin, Ralph. "The Centralia Conspiracy: Murder or Self Defense." Chicago: I.W.W., 1919; Publication (Box 10, Folder 10)
  1919?
  - Item 1: The Centralia Conspiracy: Murder or Self Defense., 1919; Publication (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Author: Ralph Chaplin
  - Item 2: The Centralia Conspiracy: Murder or Self Defense., 1919; Publication (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Chapman, C.H. "Lessons in Economics: A Textbook for Workers." Chicago: I.W.W. Educational Bureau, no date 37 pages, Publication (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Lessons in Economics: A Textbook for Workers., 1922; Publication (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Author: C. H. Chapman
  - Item 2: Lessons in Economics: A Textbook for Workers., 1922; Publication (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Chumley, L.S. "Hotel, Restaurant, and Domestic Workers." no date. 40 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Hotel, Restaurant and Domestic Workers, Publication (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Author: L. S. Chumley
- Cole, James Kelly. "Revolutionary Writings." Chicago, I.W.W., no date. 85 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Revolutionary Writings. Chicago, I.W.W., Publication (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Author: James Kelly Cole
- Costello, E.J. "The shame That is Kentucky's: The Story of the Harlan Mine War." 1932. 27 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: The Shame That Is Kentucky's: The Story of the Harlan Mine War., 1932; Publication (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Author: E. J. Costello
- DeLeon, Daniel. "The Preamble of the Industrial Workers of the World." Glasgow, Scotland: Socialist Labour Press, 1905. 31 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: The Preamble of the Industrial Workers of the World., 1905; Publication (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Author: Daniel De Leon
    Notes: Address delivered at Union Temple, Minneapolis, July 10, 1905.
  - Item 2: The Preamble of the Industrial Workers of the World., 1905; Publication (Box 10, Folder 15)
- DeLeon, Daniel. "The Preamble of the Industrial Workers of the World." Address delivered at Union Temple, Minneapolis, July 10, 1905. New York: Labor News Company, 50 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 16)
  July 10, 1905
  - Item 1: The Preamble of the Industrial Workers of the World., Publication (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Item 2: The Preamble of the Industrial Workers of the World., Publication (Box 10, Folder 16)
- DeLeon, Daniel and Eugene Debs. "Industrial Unionism." New York: New York Labor News Company, 1919. 10 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Industrial Unionism., 1919; Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Author: Daniel De Leon; Eugene V. Debs
  - Item 2: Industrial Unionism., 1905; Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Author: Eugene V. Debs
- "Do We Need More Sedition Laws?" New York: American civil Liberties Union, 1920. 22 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Do We Need More Sedition Laws?, 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Author: Alfred Bettman; Swinburne Hale
- Duff, Harvey. "The Silent Defenders, Courts and Capitalism in California." Chicago, I.W.W. no date. 112 pages, Publication (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: The Silent Defenders, Courts and Capitalism in California., Publication (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Author: Harvey Duff
  - Item 2: The Silent Defenders, Courts and Capitalism in California., Publication (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Dunn, William F. "The Crime of Centralia." Butte: 1919, 16 pages., Publication (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: The Crime of Centralia. Butte:, 1919; Publication (Box 10, Folder 20)
    Author: William F. Dunn
- Ebert, Justus. "The I.W.W. in Theory and Practice." 2nd and 3rd edition, Chicago: I.W.W., 124 pages, Publication (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: The I.W.W. in Theory and Practice., 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Author: Justus Ebert
  - Item 2: The I.W.W. in Theory and Practice., 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Notes: Second edition. Copy 2.
  - Item 3: The I.W.W. in Theory and Practice., Publication (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Item 4: The I.W.W. in Theory and Practice., Publication (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Ebert, Justus. "The Trial of a New Society." Cleveland, I.W.W., no date. 117 page manuscripts, Publication (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: The Launching of the Industrial Workers of the World, 1913; Publication (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Notes: University of California Publications in Economics, v.4:no.1 (1913:Nov. 25)
- Council of the Churches of Christ in America. "The Centralia Case: A Joint Report on the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia." Washington, November 11, 1919. New York, 1930. 48 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The Centralia Case: A Joint Report on the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia., 1930; Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Author: Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America.
    Notes: Washington, Nov. 11, 1919.
  - Item 2: The Centralia Case: A Joint Report on the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia., 1930; Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Notes: Washington, Nov. 11, 1919. Copy 2.
- "The Fight for Free Speech." New York: American Civil Liberties Union, 1921. 31 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The Fight For Free Speech., 1921; Publication (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Author: American Civil Liberties Union
- Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley. "Sabotage." Cleveland: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, April 1915. 31 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  April 1915
  - Item 1: Sabotage., 1915; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Author: Elizabeth Gurley Flynn
    Notes: April 1915. 31 p.
- George, Harrison. "The I.W.W. Trial." Chicago: I.W.W., 1918. 208 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The I.W.W. Trial., 1918; Publication (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Author: Harrison George; A. S. Embree
- George, Harrison. "Is Freedom Dead?" Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1918. 24 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Is Freedom Dead?, 1918; Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Author: Harrison George
- Glynn, T. See: Hanson, Nils. H., Publication (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: John Neuhouse: Wobbly Folklorist, 1960; Publication (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Author: Archie Green
    Notes: University of Illinois Bulletin, Reprint Series no.88. Reprinted from Journal of American Folklore, v.73:no.289.
- Green, Carhie. "John Neuhaus: Wobbly Folklorist." Illinois, 1960. 217 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: The Onward Sweep of the Machine Process., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Author: Nils Hanson
    Notes: Bound with Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote and The Diesel Motor.
  - Item 2: The Onward Sweep of the Machine Process., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Notes: Bound with Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote and The Diesel Motor. Copy 2.
  - Item 3: The Onward Sweep of the Machine Process., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Notes: Bound with Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote and The Diesel Motor. Rebound without original cover. Copy 3.
  - Item 4: Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Author: T. Glynn
  - Item 5: Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Item 7: The Diesel Motor., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Author: Barbara L. Frankenthal
  - Item 8: The Diesel Motor., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Item 9: The Diesel Motor., Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Hanson, Nils. "The Onward Sweep of the Machine Process." Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, no date, 8 pages. And Glynn, T. "Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote." 12 pages and Frankenthal, Barbara L. "The Diesel Motor." 12 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Speech of Wm. D. Haywood on the Case of Ettor and Giovannitti., 1912; Publication (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Author: William D. Haywood
- Haywood, William D. "The General Strike." Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1911. 18 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Patriotism and the Worker., 1912; Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Author: Gustave Herve
  - Item 2: Patriotism and the Worker., 1912; Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Haywood, William D. "Speech of Wm. D. Haywood on the Case of Ettor and Giovannitti." Lawrence, Massachusetts: Ettor-Giovanitti Defense Committee, 1912. 16 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Craft Unionism - Why It Fails., 1933; Publication (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Author: I.W.W. (Industrial Workers of the World)
- Gustave Herve. "Patriotism and the Worker." Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1912. 32 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Dollars and Steel Against Humanity: Iron Ore Miners Strike., 1916; Publication (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Item 2: Dollars and Steel Against Humanity: Iron Ore Miners Strike., 1916; Publication (Box 11, Folder 11)
- I.W.W. "Craft Unionism - Why It Fails." Chicago: I.W.W. 1922. 46 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: An Economic Interpretation of the Job., 1923; Publication (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: An Economic Interpretation of the Job., 1923; Publication (Box 11, Folder 12)
- I.W.W. "Dollars and Steel Against Humanity: Iron Ore Miners Strike." Cleveland, I.W.W., 1916, 12 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Ettor and Giovannitti Before the Jury at Salem, Mass., November 23, 1912., Publication (Box 11, Folder 13)
- I.W.W. "An Economic Interpretation of the Job." Chicago, 1923. 61 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Evidence and Cross-Examination of J.T. (Red) Doran in the Case of the U.S.A. vs. Wm. D. Haywood et al., 1918; Publication (Box 11, Folder 14)
- I.W.W. "Ettor and Giovannitti Before the Jury of Salem, Massachusetts, November 23, 1912." Chicago: I.W.W. 1912. 80 pages., Publication (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: The General Strike for Industrial Freedom.., 1933; Publication (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Item 2: The General Strike for Industrial Freedom.., 1933; Publication (Box 11, Folder 15)